SOPHIE GRAHAM

WEB DEVELOPER

+447 835 852 876

sophiegraham@btinternet.com

ilkley, Leeds

https://sophiegraham99.github.io/portfolio-app/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sophie-elizabeth-graham/

A forward-thinking web developer focused on staying up to date with the latest web technologies and design trends. Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, WordPress, and WooCommerce, I specialise in crafting interactive, responsive, and accessible web experiences.

WORK EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPER | 2023 - PRESENT

Unbranded Digital, Bradford

- Spearheaded the development of 9+ bespoke websites across a diverse range of industries, from brief to launch
- Implemented animation tools like GSAP to create dynamic animations and scroll effects that elevate the users experience.
- Collaborated closely with the SEO team to devise UX driven strategies, resulting in a 40% surge in click-through rates for a prominent ecommerce platform
- Implemented performance optimisation techniques such as image compression, lazy loading, and minification to enhance website speed, load times, and overall user experience
- Managed updates and security patches for a portfolio of 30+
 WordPress websites, ensuring 99% uptime
- Taking the lead in the redesign and development of the digital agency's website

• BARTENDER | 2021 - 2022

Ouseburn Gardens, Newcastle

• DOMESTIC ASSISTANT | 2021

MMCG Care Home, Ilkley

KITCHEN ASSISTANT | 2016 - 2018

MMCG Care Home, Ilkley

REFERENCES

References are available upon request

EDUCATION

COMPUTER SCIENCE MSc

Northumbria University | 2021 - 2023

MECHANICAL ENGINEERING BENG

Newcastle University | 2018 - 2021

A LEVELS

Mathematics, Chemistry, Physics | 2018

LANGUAGES	
JavaScript	
HTML	
CSS/SaSS	
PHP	
WordPress	

SKILLS

- UI/UX Design Expertise
- Strong Client Communication Skills
- Ecommerce
- Website Performance Optimisation
- Responsive & Adaptive Design Proficiency
- Effective Collaboration
- WordPress CMS